<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> <rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"> <channel> <title>Robobo</title> <description>A Proudly Mozambican Aplications, Software and IoT development agency. We are innovation. You provide the project and we use the latest tools and resources to provide you the best solution.</description> <link>http://www.robobo.org/</link> <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/> <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2016 21:26:35 +0200</pubDate> <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2016 21:26:35 +0200</lastBuildDate> <generator>Jekyll v3.3.1</generator> <item> <title>Website da Moz Devz</title> <description>Desenvolvimento do novo website da comunidade &lt;a href=&quot;http://mozdevz.org/&quot;&gt;MozDevz.org&lt;/a&gt;. O website implementa a melhor technologia responsiva, isto é, adapta-se ao ecrã em que está a ser visualizado (perfeito em smartphones assim como em browsers web no PC). Pode ser visitado em &lt;a href=&quot;http://mozdevz.org/&quot;&gt;www.MozDevz.org&lt;/a&gt;</description> <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate> <link>http://www.robobo.org/website/2015/05/28/project-8/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.robobo.org/website/2015/05/28/project-8/</guid> <category>Website</category> </item> <item> <title>Moz News</title> <description>Desenvolvimento do primeiro agregador de notícias de Moçambique em Android. Este é um public beta preview. O aplicativo foi testado em dispositivos com versão Android 2.3.7, 42.2 e 5.0.2. Sendo ideal para telefones e Tablets. Pode ser baixado agora em &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.robobo.app.moznews&quot;&gt;Moznews no Google Play&lt;/a&gt; A MozNews é um aplicativo desenvolvido sem fins lucrativos, com um objetivo, de agregar notícias das diversas fontes noticiosas Moçambicanas e apresentar as mesmas de forma otimizada e eficiente nos dispositivos móveis. O desenvolvimento desta solução surgiu de uma necessidade de estar atualizado às notícias Nacionais pelo telemóvel, mas na altura de desenvolvimento da solução (Agosto de 2013), nenhuma das fontes noticiosas em Moçambique tinha uma versão dos seus sites otimizada para o smartphone e muito menos era responsivo, algo que causava frustração ao aceder os sites pelo telemóvel e ter de encarar uma experiência direcionada às telas grandes, como aos do computador. Como uma primeira fase o aplicativo foi desenvolvido para a plataforma Android e a publicação foi feita na Play Store (mercado de aplicativos da plataforma Android). Devido à falta de recursos para continuar o desenvolvimento para as outras plataformas, como o iOS (Apple iPhone), Windows Phone, entre outros, uma solução conhecida por Responsive-Web foi implementada para não deixar de lado usuários naquelas plataformas, que podem aceder a uma experiência semelhante e otimizada pelo navegador de Internet dos telemóveis, simplesmente acedendo à página http://mozapp.necto.me/. O aplicativo foi publicado inicialmente como Open Source em plataforma de colaboração e publicação de código, conhecida como Github, com objetivo de permitir que outros desenvolvedores pudessem ver como o aplicativo foi desenvolvido e caso alguém pretende replicar, melhorar ou criar uma solução com base no trabalho feito, a opção existe. O aplicativo continua a ser desenvolvido e mantido em operação durante tempos livres e conta com mais de 1000 (mil) pessoas que já baixaram o aplicativo para os telemóveis. Neste momento os jornais O Pais online e @Verdade estão disponível no aplicativo, e a informação é carregada ou agregada de forma automática. O desenvolvedor espera adicionar mais fontes noticiosas e tornar o aplicativo o ponto de referência para aceder informação nacional de forma otimizada nos telemóveis.</description> <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate> <link>http://www.robobo.org/android%20application/2013/10/25/project-7/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.robobo.org/android%20application/2013/10/25/project-7/</guid> <category>Android Application</category> </item> <item> <title>3D Find It</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;New 3Dpartsource.com site and Android app released to great international acclaim!&quot;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; This revolutionary part sourcing platform instantly matches buyers with suppliers and manufacturers of industrial components using 3D shape alone. It makes part sourcing simple, instant, free and global. For suppliers, it expands market access, slashes marketing costs and streamlines the customer acquisition and lead generation process. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://3dindustri.es/2013/03/27/launch-of-new-3dpartsource-com-site-and-app/&quot;&gt;3dindustri.es Announcement of the app&lt;/a&gt;. On their website, you can find out more about our exciting work.</description> <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate> <link>http://www.robobo.org/android%20-%20ios%20-%20web%20development/2013/02/14/project-5/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.robobo.org/android%20-%20ios%20-%20web%20development/2013/02/14/project-5/</guid> <category>Android - iOS - Web Development</category> </item> <item> <title>Interfacing Hardware the Easy Way with Android and Arduino (Talk)</title> <description>There are many techniques and options for using your Android Smartphone to interface with hardware projects you may create using Arduino, but with so many options it can be hard getting started with development. I will therefore take you through a quick getting started with creating and interfacing with a hardware project in minutes. I will talk through setting up hardware, tips and tricks on which hardware to choose down to designing your Android App that bridges software and hardware in minutes. By the end of the talk, everyone will be designing apps that can interact in some way with the real world. &lt;a href=&quot;http://uk.droidcon.com/2012/sessions/interfacing-hardware-the-easy-way-with-android-and-arduino/&quot;&gt;Droidcon London 2012&lt;/a&gt;</description> <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate> <link>http://www.robobo.org/iot%20-%20conferences/2012/10/25/project-6/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.robobo.org/iot%20-%20conferences/2012/10/25/project-6/</guid> <category>IoT - Conferences</category> </item> <item> <title>3D Printing Necto Hardware</title> <description>&lt;p&gt; From development of CAD drawings, PCB architecture to preparation of the print work, we made the Necto product line come to life. We took advantage of an Open Source project, the RepRap and made our entire hardware prototype come to life. This feature is purely Robobo. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Video Demo&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/KwISKA9waEc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description> <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate> <link>http://www.robobo.org/3d%20printing/2012/04/02/project-9/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.robobo.org/3d%20printing/2012/04/02/project-9/</guid> <category>3D Printing</category> </item> <item> <title>Necto Android Application (An Arduino Controller)</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;The Necto Android Application is where users are able to control a Necto Hardware. The controller can also be used with any Arduino Project as long as the correct configuration is made (more information to be added to our Wiki). This is an application that provides various features depending on the hardware and many more are to be released! The application is designed as a centralized gateway to most projects and products, hardware and features of hardware published here at Robobo. There is no need to look though separate applications when everything is in one place, convenient.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Below are a few screen shots of the application's User Interface.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/portfolio/necto_app/screen1.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Necto Usense Prototype Images&quot; width=&quot;190&quot; height=&quot;320&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;img/portfolio/necto_app/screen_bt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Necto Usense Prototype Images&quot; width=&quot;190&quot; height=&quot;320&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;img/portfolio/necto_app/Usense_options.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Necto Usense Prototype Images&quot; width=&quot;190&quot; height=&quot;320&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/portfolio/necto_app/Alarm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Necto Usense Prototype Images&quot; width=&quot;190&quot; height=&quot;320&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;img/portfolio/necto_app/airRuler.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Necto Usense Prototype Images&quot; width=&quot;190&quot; height=&quot;320&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;img/portfolio/necto_app/lamp_multicolor_UI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Necto Usense Prototype Images&quot; width=&quot;190&quot; height=&quot;320&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/portfolio/necto_app/lamp_options.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Necto Usense Prototype Images&quot; width=&quot;190&quot; height=&quot;320&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;img/portfolio/necto_app/rc_UI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Necto Usense Prototype Images&quot; width=&quot;190&quot; height=&quot;320&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;img/portfolio/necto_app/voice_rc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Necto Usense Prototype Images&quot; width=&quot;190&quot; height=&quot;320&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</description> <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate> <link>http://www.robobo.org/android%20-%20iot%20(internet%20of%20things)/2012/04/02/project-4/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.robobo.org/android%20-%20iot%20(internet%20of%20things)/2012/04/02/project-4/</guid> <category>Android - IoT (Internet of Things)</category> </item> <item> <title>Necto AnyRC</title> <description>Introducing the Necto anyRC &lt;p&gt;This is an exciting new product from Robobo that enables any remote controlled toy car to be effortlessly modified and accept to be controlled by their Android Smartphone. There are 3 easy steps to enable a cheap radio controlled toy car to be turned into a smart and feature packed toy. Bring life to that boring controller.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;b&gt;Hardware Features&lt;/b&gt; &lt;p&gt;This device features an enclosure for the modified Radio Controlled toy car and is made to be compact. This version can be powered by removable battery (recommended) or via USB.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;b&gt;Current Application Features&lt;/b&gt; &lt;p&gt;The mobile application brings the once boring toy to life by providing the following&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Voice control enabling you to easily command the car to move at a certain direction. Touch control giving you the easy and fancy User Interface that just works! Accelerometer control allowing you to orient the phone in a respective direction and the remote controlled car responds accordingly. Above all, have we mentioned how much convenient and cooler it is to simply take your phone out and control a toy car?! Yes we know this will please many.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/portfolio/anyrc/necto_anyRcdemo.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Necto Usense Prototype Images&quot; width=&quot;557&quot; height=&quot;241&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;b&gt;Video Demo&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/YPoZA2stVVU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description> <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate> <link>http://www.robobo.org/iot%20(internet%20of%20things)/2012/04/02/project-3/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.robobo.org/iot%20(internet%20of%20things)/2012/04/02/project-3/</guid> <category>IoT (Internet of Things)</category> </item> <item> <title>Necto Lamp</title> <description>&lt;p&gt; Introducing the Necto light, a different approach in light interfacing. A device that gives you many options and functions that you will actually forget that it is just a simple lamp. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;b&gt;Hardware Features&lt;/b&gt; &lt;p&gt; This device version works with Red, Green and Blue LEDs permitting for different colours to be chosen from within the mobile application. This version can be powered by removable battery or via USB.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;b&gt;Current Application Features&lt;/b&gt; &lt;p&gt; The lamp when controlled from the mobile provides great features such as:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;b&gt;AMARINO'S MULTICOLOR LAMP &lt;/b&gt; &lt;p&gt;This feature as the name suggests, is not our own. We use it here for one main reason which is to show developers how easy it is to make their existing project from Amarino into Necto. For the end user, well it provides the excellent ability to manually control the colour of light on the lamp and let you play around to find your favourite colour. Brighten up your room in a different way.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;b&gt;THE VISUAL METRONOME &lt;/b&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is an exciting feature that will keep musicians and dancers tune. This feature enables users to set the tempo from their mobile and have the results displayed to them. No more tic-tac sounds, unless you really want it and we can include the feature. No more excuses for being off beat. This feature is purely Robobo.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/portfolio/ulamp/necto_lamps.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Necto Usense Prototype Images&quot; width=&quot;557&quot; height=&quot;241&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;b&gt;Video Demo&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/18WBX1-ytj4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description> <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate> <link>http://www.robobo.org/iot%20(internet%20of%20things)/2012/04/02/project-2/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.robobo.org/iot%20(internet%20of%20things)/2012/04/02/project-2/</guid> <category>IoT (Internet of Things)</category> </item> <item> <title>Necto Usense</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;Introducing the Necto Usense, a revolutionary and practical device that will enable users to take measurements effortlessly and provide extra features like reminder based on positioning of the device, security control and much more. The device is one of the first in our portfolio of hybrid production and distribution products. This means that users are able to benefit from this device and its features very soon. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;b&gt;Hardware Features&lt;/b&gt;&lt;p&gt;This device version features an Ultrasonic range finder capable of measuring up to 5 meters (note that this can be extended to greater distances, the cost increases depending on the maximum distance required). This version can be powered by removable battery or via USB.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;b&gt;Current Application Features&lt;/b&gt; &lt;p&gt; The device on its own is not much, although functions can be enabled for it to carry out various standalone functions, we intend that it is used with our Android Necto Controller application which includes the following features. Note that the following list will be updated accordingly as the application is developed further. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/portfolio/usense/usense-prototype-to-real-side-by-side.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Necto Usense Prototype Images&quot; width=&quot;557&quot; height=&quot;241&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;b&gt;Video Demo&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/UCB8tsL8tjY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description> <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate> <link>http://www.robobo.org/iot%20(internet%20of%20things)/2012/04/02/project-1/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.robobo.org/iot%20(internet%20of%20things)/2012/04/02/project-1/</guid> <category>IoT (Internet of Things)</category> </item> </channel> </rss>